Harris Hawthorne Wilder Papers, 1868-1975 [Bulk Dates: 1882-1928]
Smith College Archives
- Series VI. Professional Activities
  - Publications
    - Publications: "Physical Correspondence in Two Sets of Duplicate Twins," (reprint) 1919 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Publications: "A Ginling College Essay," (reprint) 1920 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Publications: "Indian Corn-hills in Massachusetts," (reprint) 1920 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Publications: A Laboratory Manual of Anthropometry 1920 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Publications: "Anthropometric Measurements," (reprint) 1921 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Publications: "Racial Differences in Palm and Sole Configuration III: Palm and Sole Prints of Japanese and Chinese," (reprint) 1922 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Publications: "[Memorial to] Robert Wiedersheim," (reprint) 1923 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Publications: "Notes on the Indians of Southern Massachusetts," (reprint) 1923 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Publications: Man's Prehistoric Past, 1923 (Box 12)
      - A. Galleys of figures; illustrations (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - B. Reviews (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - C. Copy inscribed by author (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Publications: "The Phylogeny of the Human Foot: The Testimony Presented by the Configuration of the Friction Ridges," (reprint) 1924 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Publications: "The Bodily Proportions of Women in the United States: Based Upon Measurements Taken from One Hundred Smith College Students," (draft) 1924 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Publications: "[A Review of] Manual of the Vertebrates of the United States," (reprint) 1924 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Publications: "Palm and Sole Studies VIII. Occurrence of Primitive Patterns (Whorls)," (reprint) 1925 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Publications: "Palm and Sole Studies IX: The Morphology of the Hypothenar of the Hand: A Study in the Variation and Degeneration of a Typical Pattern," (reprint) 1926 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Publications: The Pedigree of the Human Race, 1926 (Box 12)
      - A. Original Manuscript: preface: table of contents (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - B. Original Manuscript: Chapters I (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - C. Original Manuscript: Chapter II (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - D. Original Manuscript: Chapter III (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - E. Original Manuscript: Chapter IV (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - F. Original Manuscript: Chapter V (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - G. Original Manuscript: additions and revisions (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - H. Original Manuscript: list of illustrations; illustrations; photographs (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - I. Original Manuscript: reviews (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - J. Copy inscribed by author (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Publications: "Study of Error in Interpretation and Formulation of Palmar Dermatoglyphics," (reprint) 1928 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Publications: "Revised Methods of Interpretation and Formulation of Palmar Dermatoglyphics," (reprint) 1929 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Bound volume of 13 HHW reprints 1904-1918 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Illustrations, unidentified, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts
    - Unpublished Manuscripts (arranged alphabetically): "Acanthias Vulgaris," undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts: "A Comparison of the Bones of the Skull of Desmognathus Fusca and Spelerpes Bislineatus," undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts: "The Larynx of Pipa Americana," undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts: Outlines of Anthropology, undated (Box 15)
      - A. Early manuscript undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - B. 1908 manuscript (copy) (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - C. 1909 manuscript (original) (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - D. 1914 manuscript (copy) (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - E. "Part 11: Ethnology" (copy) undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - F. "Part III: Ethnology" (copy) undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - G. Miscellaneous notes and revisions undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - H. Tracings of Text Figures undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts: <unittitle>Outlines of Culture-History</unittitle>, undated (Box 15)
      - A. Introduction (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - B. Chapter I "Man's View: Self and the World." (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - C. Chapter II "The Use and Control of Fire." (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - D. Chapter III "Tools and Their Use." (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - E. Chapter IV "Basketry and Weaving." (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - F. Chapter VII "Hunting and Fishing; Warfare." (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - G. Chapter VIII "Domestication of Animals." (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - H. Chapter IX "Domestication of Plants: Agriculture." (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - I. Chapter X "Roads', Transportation; Orientation." (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - J. Chapter X [XI] "Weights and Measures; Space and Time." (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - K. Chapter XII "Decoration and Dress." (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - L. Chapter XIII "Spoken Language." (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - M. Chapter XVI "Games and Sports; Mime and Pageantry." (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - N. Chapter XVIII "Fine-Arts." (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - O. Chapter XX "Philosophy." (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - P. Notes (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts: "Outlines of Human Morphology," undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts: "Outlines of Zoology," undated (Box 16)
      - A. Table of Contents, Introduction, Vertebrates (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - B. Mammalia, Samopsida, Ichthyopsida (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - C. Prevertebrata: Articulata (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - D. Articulata (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - E. Arachnoidea (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - F. Carbon copy of manuscript (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts: "The Phalangeal Patterns of the Human Toes," undated [1918-1919] (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Speeches
    - Speeches (arranged chronologically), "Butterflies and Moths of Hampshire County," 1885 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Speeches: "The Work of Charles Darwin," 1909 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Speeches: "The Origin of European Civilization," 1909 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Speeches: "The Val Soda," 1909 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Speeches: "The Beginning of Human History," 1910 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Speeches: "The Teaching of Latin and Greek," 1912 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Speeches: "The Origin of the Greek," undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Speeches: "Popular Lectures" (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Research
    - Research: Anthropometry (unprocessed) (Box 19)
    - Research: Anthropornetry (unprocessed) (Box 20)
    - Research: Dermatoglyphics (unprocessed) (Box 21)
    - Research: Dermatoglyphics (unprocessed) (Box 22)
    - Research: Dermatoglyphics (unprocessed) (Box 23)
    - Research: Dermatoglyphics (unprocessed) (Box 24)
    - Research: Dermatoglyphics (unprocessed) (Box 25)
    - Research: Dermatoglyphics (unprocessed) (Box 26)
    - Research: Dermatoglyphics (unprocessed) (Box 27)
    - Research: Dermatoglyphics (unprocessed) (Box 28)
    - Research: New England Indian Files 1904-1920 (Box 29)
      - "Indian Place Names--Massachusetts" undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - "Indian History in Massachusetts" undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - "Pocumtucks" undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Notes on Indians--Northampton & Laurel Park, Massachusetts 1913, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Northampton, Indian Hill & Hadley 1904-1920 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - "Field Notebook #3 --Hadley, & Cheapside/Greenfield, Massachusetts 1915-1917 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - "Rhode Island Early History" 1904, 1912, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - An Account of Excavation of Fort Neck Cemetary--Charlestown, Rhode Island 1912 September (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Field Notebook #1 --Charlestown, Rhode Island; Field Notebook #2 --Hadley/Hatfield, Massachusetts 1912 Summer (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Penobscot, Maine 1910, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - "Roots in Algonkin Place Name" undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - Clippings Concerning Indians, Notes, and Photographs 1908-1917 (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - Notebooks (3): undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
        - "Indian Aborigines" (Box 29, Folder 13)
        - "Primitive Music" (Box 29, Folder 13)
        - Unidentified (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - "Quotations from Early Explorers concerning the conditions of the country of Southern New England" undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - Maps, Topographical of New England 1914, 1920 (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - "Maps of New England" undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Notes, Maps & Miscellaneous on Indians 1887, undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - Scorebook of Primitive Music--incomplete undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Research: Teratology (unprocessed) (Box 30)
    - Research: Other (unprocessed) (Box 31)
    - Research: Other (unprocessed) (Box 32)
  - Teaching and Research Tools
    - Teaching and Research Tools: (unprocessed) (Box 33)
    - Teaching and Research Tools: Bust [Cope?] (unprocessed) (Box 34)
    - Teaching and Research Tools: Reprint Collection (unprocessed) (Box 35)
    - Teaching and Research Tools: Slide Collection (unprocessed) (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous (unprocessed) (Box 37)
- Oversize Materials
  - Oversize Materials: (1) (unprocessed) (Box 38)
  - Oversize Materials: (2) (unprocessed) (Box 39)
  - Oversize Materials: (3) (unprocessed) (Box 40)
  - Oversize Materials: (4) (unprocessed) (Box 41)